Finding Aid for the Albert McCleery Papers PASC.0098
UCLA Library Special Collections
- THEATER FILES, Eary 1940s, 1950s and 1960s; (Boxes 4, 7, 14, 16, and 18)
  - PASADENA PLAYHOUSE alumni and ex-students name and addresses, program requirements and budget figures, no date (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - PASADENA PLAYHOUSE Board of Trustees minutes and reports (Approximately 35 items), 1956, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Pasadena Playhouse College of Theatre Arts Application for Re- Accreditation, [1967?] (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - PASADENA PLAYHOUSE financial reports (12 items), 1956, 1962, 1968 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    With Report on Economic Study, and preliminary fiscal report.
  - PASADENA PLAYHOUSE memorabilia (24 items), 1956, 1957, 1962 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    Clipings on McCleery joining the Playhouse, play programs, schedules, and Proposal of Television Equipment.
  - Publicity photographs of stage productions (Approximately 25 items), no date (Box 18, Folder 5)
    Some appear to represent Fordham University.
  - Theatre School Ion - catalogue and brochures, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - THRESHOLD THEATRE proposal, budgets and contracts (21 items), 1961 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Yale and the IVY Radio Network - correspondence (11 items), 1953, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    With prospectus from Ivy Network.
- CONFERENCES AND SPEAKING ENGAGEMENTS, 1953-1962; (Boxes 4, 13, and 17)
  The series documents assorted conferences and speaking engagements in which McCleery may have been present at such as American Educational Theatre Association, Armed Forces Television Conference and Westinghouse Educational Television Conference among others. Additionally there is University of British Columbia correspondence and photographs of McCleery working at the University and transcript of speech Theater's Debt to Television. The series is arranged alphabetically by event or location name.
  - Albert McCleery photographs, invitations and speech transcript (7 items)., 1954 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    Three photographs of Mccleery (conference unknown), two invitations for appearances, and transcript of speech "Theater's Debt to Television".
  - American Educational Theatre Association conference schedule, membership directory, reports and correspondence (9 items), 1953 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - CBS Television Workshop Seminar questionnaires (56 items), 1960 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Seventh Annual Summer Television Workshop (Michigan State) notebook (1 item)., 1957 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Syracuse University correspondence and Speech Association of the Eastern States convention program (4 items), 1961 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Third Annual Armed Forces Television Conference brochures (7 items), 1962 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    On the role of television within the Army and Air Force.
  - Third Annual Armed Forces Television Conference schedule of TV presentations, brochures on TV as an instructional medium and its role in the armed forces (9 items), 1962 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - TV Code Committee and High School of Art and Design letters regarding appearances (2 items), 1955, 1962 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - University of British Columbia correspondence and photographs of McCleery working at the University (20 items), 1962 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Westinghouse Educational Television Conference correspondence and schedule (16 items), 1961 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    With brochures from WQED, WQEX, and KQED television stations.
- PERSONAL FILES, 1950s, 1960s, early-1970s; (Boxes 2, 14, 16, 19, and 20)
  The Personal Files series consists of memorabilia, notes for what appears to be a possible lecture, material related to Fordham University, and information regarding McCleery's credits.
  - Accounting, 1955, 1962 (Box 20, Folder 12)
    Correspondence and lists on bills, money received, expenditures and other personal accounting matters. Approximately 45 items.
  - Albert McCleery credits and biographies (13 items), 1950, 1955, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Awards and Memorabilia, 1950's, 1960's (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Emmy Awards programs and entry forms, Institute Of Education By Radio-TV award, NBC MATINEE THEATRE, CAMEO THEATRE, INHERITANCE memorabilia. 1950's, 1960's. 20 items.
  - FORDHAM UNIVERSITY, 1950's (Box 20, Folder 14)
    Programs, clippings, exams, scripts, and correspondence relating to the University. 25 items.
  - Invitations for a party given by McCleery (4 items), 1960 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - The Lombardy in New York, ca. 1957-1960 (Box 20, Folder 13)
    Bills, lease, and correspondence relating to rental apartment. Ca. 30 items.
  - Macloren Productions, Inc, 1970-71 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    Assets, correspondence and legal materials relating to the company and its Macloren Playhouse. 21 items.
  - Memorabilia, no date (Box 19, Folder 2)
    Credit cards, clipping, Christmas money pool with Stephen Sondheim and Joseph Chaikin.
  - Notes [for class, lecture?], [1930?] (Box 16, Folder 6)
    Personal notes (class, lecture?) on theater, literature, debate. [1930?]. Approximately 20 items.
  - Party bills, menu and list of guests for two parties given by McCleery, 1953, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Photographs of McCleery as a young man, wedding and from friends (18 items), no date (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Telephone list, 1963 (Box 20, Folder 11)
    Lists of names and telephone numbers of McCleery's friends and colleagues in Southern California. 1963. 6 items.